So I'm back on heroku and I created an account which is why I'm in my dashboard now.
If you haven't done that, definitely do so,
click on sign up, create a new account, enter your data and you should end up on a similar dashboard and
have a create new app button somewhere.
Now when you click that, on heroku you can give your app a name and I'll name it
node complete udemy, the name is up to you of course.
You can choose a region,
I'll go with Europe because I'm located there but that is up to you of course and you can then simply
click on create app.
Now with that clicked, you can now choose a couple of different things.
First of all, we can ignore the pipeline feature, here
deployment method will use heroku git,
now what is git? Git is a tool which is not part of heroku but used by heroku. Git is a version control
system and as such, it's a tool which you can use,
it's totally optional but it helps a lot with saving and managing your source code.
It allows you to work with so-called commits, branches and remote repositories to name some of its most
important features. Commits are basically snapshots of your code which you can take
but when you can always switch, so you can always go back to the older version of your code and have
a look at it and then go back to your most recent one or rollback to an older commit,
so this allows you to revert to older snapshots easily or well safely add it to your code because you can
always go back,
now you can create commits after you fix some bugs, after you add new features and so on.
Branches also allow you to not just have one history of snapshots but multiple histories for different
versions of your code,
so you could have a master branch where your production ready code is in and then you want to fix bugs
or add new features in other branches
so that your main code is untouched
but when a new feature done, you can do something which is called merging and merge the new feature branch
with your main branch so that you have one branch which you can put back into production again
but it allows you to work on different features in different branches without affecting your main finished
code for now
and this allows you to basically separate your development workflow from let's say, the new feature or
bug fixing to production workflow. Remote repositories,
that simply means that your code is not only stored locally as it is by default but that you can store
it and its commit and branches in the cloud and that of course means that you can protect against loss
of local data and you can also access your source code from different machines and share it with other
developers of course and you can also use that feature to deploy your code automatically
and that is what heroku does because you will essentially use heroku as a remote repository
which means when you push your code to that remote repository, to heroku, it will then be taken by heroku
and it will be put into production and a server will be spun up based on it automatically.
That is what git is and that is what heroku uses here.
Now that means that you will need git and for that you can simply google for git and then it's this link
here,
gitscm.com
and there you can simply click downloads and download it for your operating system.
Simply download the installer for your operating system here and walk through the steps presented there
and thereafter, you'll have git installed.
Now check the documentation in case you are facing any problems and also attached to this video,
you'll find some free links to get you started with git
in case you want to learn more about it. For the deployment
only, you don't really need to become a git expert though,
you only need it installed. Once you did that,
let's continue with the rest of the deployment process here.